evans.co.uk 2016-10-09

# Privacy & Cookies - Evans

### Privacy Policy

**References in this Privacy Policy Statement to "we", "us" and "Evans" are to Evans Retail Limited (trading as Evans).**

At Evans we are committed to maintaining your privacy. Our privacy policy statement is given below. If we make changes to this policy, we will notify you by updating this statement on our Website.

**What information do we collect?**  
We ask for your name, telephone number, home address, email address and age for competitions, sweepstakes, or newsletter sign ups. When a purchase is made on our site, in addition to the above, we also ask for delivery address, and payment method details. We may obtain information about your usage of our Website to help us develop and improve it further through online surveys and other requests.

**What the data will be used for?**  
Your data will enable us, and our processors, to fulfil your order, to notify you about important functionality changes and for statistical or survey purposes to improve this website and our services to you. We may also send you from time to time (by email or post) information about products and services and details of promotions and special offers from Evans. If you do not wish to be contacted for these purposes, we offer a range of ways in which you can inform us about your marketing preferences:

•  all email messages and email newsletters will contain information on how you can unsubscribe; or  
•  email our customer services team by [clicking here](https://www.evans.co.uk/webapp/wcs/stores/servlet/ContactUs?catalogId=33054&storeId=12553&krypto=1W5XNcaiODDn4QR2OWLnAg%3D%3D&ddkey=http:ContactUs); writing "unsubscribe" in the subject heading; or  
•  call our customer services team by using the relevant number shown in the ["Contact Us"](http://www.evans.co.uk/webapp/wcs/stores/servlet/CatalogNavigationSearchResultCmd?catalogId=33054&storeId=12553&langId=-1&viewAllFlag=false&categoryId=278057&interstitial=true&TS=1316168327862#fragment-8) section; or  
•  write to us at: Customer Services, Arcadia Group Limited, Colegrave House, 70 Berners Street, London W1T 3NL

In assessing your request for goods or services, we may use your information for the purposes of the prevention and detection of fraud.

**What information do we share with others?**  
We may contract with other companies to provide certain services, including credit card processing, shipping, name and address verification, email distribution, market research, marketing and advertising services (including advertising on third party websites, social media networks and profiling) and promotions management. We provide these companies with only the information they need to perform their services and work closely with them to ensure that your privacy is respected and protected. These companies are prohibited by contract from using this information for their own marketing purposes or from sharing this information with anyone other than Evans. We may share your information with other Arcadia Group companies for internal business purposes (for example administering e-receipts or responding to customer queries). We may transfer personal data that we collect from you to third party data processors located in countries that are outside of the European Economic Area and to other Arcadia group companies in connection with the above purposes. Any such transfer of your personal data will be carried out in compliance with applicable laws and we will treat the information in a manner consistent with this Privacy Policy Statement. However, we will not pass your information on to any other Arcadia Group companies or other third parties for their own marketing purposes unless you have agreed for us to do so.

One of the purposes for which we may disclose your address and postcode details is to check against the IMRG Security Alert or any other Fraud Prevention Scheme. We may also disclose specific information upon governmental request, in response to a court order, or when required by law to do so. We may also share information with companies assisting in fraud protection or investigation. We do not provide information to these agencies or companies for marketing or commercial purposes.

**Cookies**  
This website uses Cookies. For more information please click here to see our Cookie policy.

**Links to Third-Party Sites**  
In an attempt to provide you with increased value, we may from time to time include third party links on our Website. These linked sites have separate and independent privacy policies.  We encourage you to review those policies when you visit those sites.  This Privacy Policy Statement only covers our Website and does not cover any other website. We therefore have no responsibility or liability for the content and activities of these linked sites.

**Privacy of Children on Our Website  
**Our Website is not intended for use by children under the age of 13, and we will not knowingly collect any information from any person below the age of 13.

**Sale of assets  
**In the unlikely event that Evans or substantially all of its assets are acquired, customer information will of course be one of the transferred assets.

**Klarna**

We work with Klarna AB to offer our customers more convenient methods of payment. Klarna AB (“Klarna”) is a provider of financial services. Klarna's principal place of business is at Sveavägen 46, 111 34 Stockholm, Sweden. Klarna is registered with the Swedish companies register under the registration number 556737-0431 and licensed by and under the supervision of the Swedish Financial Supervisory Authority (www.fi.se), Box 7821, 10397 Stockholm, Sweden, and the Swedish Data Protection Authority (http://www.datainspektionen.se/in-english/), Box 8114, 10420 Stockholm, Sweden.

We need to provide Klarna with certain information about you and the order to enable Klarna to assess whether you qualify for their credit products. We need to transfer to Klarna account details such as your name, address, email address, phone number, and payment history, as well as your order details, such as payment method, shipping details, what was ordered, and similar. This will not be done if you do not select Klarna as your payment method. The further use of this data will be governed by Klarna’s [Privacy Policy](http://cdn.klarna.com/1.0/shared/content/legal/terms/Klarna/en_gb/privacy)

**COOKIE POLICY**

This website uses cookies to collect information. 

• What is a cookie?  
• Use of cookies on this website  
    • Our cookies  
    • Third party cookies  
• How to manage cookies

**  
What is a cookie?**

Cookies are small files of letters and numbers that are downloaded onto your computer or mobile or other handheld device when you access certain websites.  Cookies allow a website to recognise a user’s device and help your browser navigate through the website by allowing you to log in automatically or remembering settings you selected during earlier visits (among other functions).  Cookies do not harm your computer.  If you would like to learn more about cookies in general you can visit [www.allaboutcookies.org](http://www.allaboutcookies.org/)

**  
Use of cookies on this website**

Cookies help us to provide you with a good experience when you browse this website and allow you to make full use of the online shopping and personalised features available on this website.  We do not use cookies to collect or record information such as your name, address or payment details.

We use cookies on this website for the following main purposes:  
 • for technical purposes essential for the operation of this website, such as keeping track of your current shopping session and enabling you to proceed to checkout and pay for products;  
 • to distinguish you from other users of this website, so we can personalise your shopping experience by making this website and the advertising displayed on it more relevant to your interests and so we can remember choices you make (such as your user name, language or the country you are in) when you return to visit this website;  
 • to collect statistical information about how visitors use this website, so we can improve the way this website works and measure the success of competitions and campaigns; and  
 • to enable us to fulfil our contractual obligations to third parties, for example to pay a partner if you have made a purchase on this website by following a link from their website. 

Most web browsers automatically accept cookies.  Unless you have adjusted your browser settings so that it will refuse cookies, cookies will be set when you access this website.  By using and browsing this website, you consent to cookies being used in accordance with this Cookie Policy.  If you do not consent, you must either disable cookies or refrain from using this website.  Please go to How To Manage Cookies below for information on how to manage and disable cookies.

**  
Our Cookies** Below is a list of the main cookies that are set by us when you access this website and a description of what we use them for:

Cookie name | Cookie purpose  
---|---  
userCountry, userCurrencySymbol, user Explicit, userLangId, userLanguage, userPreferredUrl, userprefs, userSalesCatalogId, userStoreId, viewed, WC_ACTIVE_POINTER, WC_AUTHENTICATION, WC_PERSISTENT, WC_SESSION_ESTABLISHED, WC_USERACTIVITY, SessionExists, ShowAlert, arc-33056-recently-viewed, JSESSIONID, mdr_browser  | These cookies remember your preferences from previous visits, allow you to add to basket and store your shopping basket. The website wouldn't work for you without them.  
_utma, _utmb, _utmc, _utmz  | These cookies enable Google Analytics software. It helps us take and analyse visitor information such as browser usage and new visitor numbers. That information helps us to improve the website and your shopping experience, and to make our marketing campaigns relevant.  
The data stored by these cookies never shows personal details from which your individual identity can be established.  
  
_#env, _#lps, _#sess, _#srchist, _#tsa, _#uid, _#vdf | We work with DC Storm to help make our marketing campaigns more relevant. DC Storm cookies are used to help us see which marketing campaigns you click on and interact with. The data taken does not contain personal details from which your individual identity can be established.  
_qsst, _qst, _qubitTracker cookies, _qPageNum_*name of brand*  |   
These cookies enable Qubit analytics software. This software helps us take and analyse visitor information such as browser usage, new visitor numbers, response to marketing activity and shopping times. That information helps us to improve the website and your shopping experience, and to make our marketing campaigns relevant. The data stored by these cookies never shows personal details from which your individual identity can be established.  
peerius_ct, peerius_rid, peerius_sess, peerius_user | These cookies enable Peerius software. This software allows us to make recommendations of products that we think might be of interest to you, based on what you and other visitors have viewed  
s_cc, s_sq, s_vi  | These cookies enable SiteCatalyst analytics software, supplied by Adobe. This software helps us take and analyse visitor information such as browser usage, new visitor numbers, response to marketing activity and shopping times. That information helps us to improve the website and your shopping experience, and to make our marketing campaigns relevant.  
s_campaign, s_ev20, _#tsa  | These cookies show us how you found our website and which website you came from. This helps us know which of our online marketing channels is most effective. They also allow us to reward some external websites for directing you to us.  

**Flash cookies  
  
** We may display video content on evans.co.uk using Adobe Flash Player.  Adobe uses Flash cookies to improve your experience as a user.  If you wish to disable or delete a Flash cookie, please visit Adobe Flashplayer Security Settings.  Please bear in mind that if you disable Flash cookies you will be unable to access certain content on our website which uses Adobe Flash Player, such as videos.  
  
**Third party cookies**

These cookies show us how you found our website and which website you came from. This helps us know which of our online marketing channels is most effective. They also allow us to reward some external websites for directing you to us. Some cookies may be set by third parties when you visit this website.  These third parties may be suppliers who partner with us to deliver our website, companies that participate with us in affiliate marketing programmes and other third parties.  These cookies are controlled by the third parties, so please check the third-party websites for more information about these cookies and how to manage them.   These third party cookies do not collect personal data from which the third party would be able to identify individual customers.

Some of our third party partners that may set cookies on this website include:  

Business partner | Cookie purpose  
---|---  
Struq | Struq uses cookies to provide you with personalised adverts when you visit other selected websites. We would like to continue to display content that's relevant to you; however, you can choose to opt out of this type of advertising permanently by visiting <http://www.struq.com/consumer-opt-out/index.php>.  
Please note though, that if you delete your cookies too, we'll no longer know that you've opted out, so the banners from Struq will reappear when you visit other selected websites.  
Criteo | Criteo uses cookies to provide you with personalised adverts when you visit other selected websites. We would like to continue to display content that's relevant to you; however, you can choose to opt out of this type of advertising permanently by visiting <http://www.criteo.com/us/privacy-policy>  
Please note though, that if you delete your cookies too, we'll no longer know that you've opted out, so the banners from Struq will reappear when you visit other selected websites.  
ecustomeropinions.com | 

In order to provide you with a better service, occasionally we'll ask if you'd like to complete a survey. This cookie's sole purpose is to remember if we've asked you to do so recently, and it contains no personal information.  
  
Awin1, Commission Junction, Linkshare, Zanox

| 

These cookies are only set if you get to the confirmation page after checkout. It is used to track whether we then owe any money as a commission to a site (affiliate) which has referred business to us.  
  
Double Click

| 

Double Click uses cookies to help to make PPC advertising more effective. These help us to track clicks and conversions. This is part of Google's conversion tag and more information on how the cookie operates and how you can manage these cookies is available at [www.google.com/intl/en_GB/policies/technologies/ads](http://www.google.com/intl/en_GB/policies/technologies/ads/)  
  
**Social buttons**

If you 'share' evans.co.uk content with friends through social networks – such as Facebook, Google and Twitter - you may be sent cookies from these third party websites. We don't control the setting of these cookies, so we suggest you check the third-party websites for more information about their cookies and how to manage them.

**  
Flash cookies**

We may display video content on evans.co.uk using Adobe Flash Player.  Adobe uses Flash cookies to improve your experience as a user.  If you wish to disable or delete a Flash cookie, please visit Adobe Flashplayer Security Settings.  Please bear in mind that if you disable Flash cookies you will be unable to access certain content on our website which uses Adobe Flash Player, such as videos.

**  
How to Manage Cookies**

You can enable or disable cookies by changing your website browser settings to accept or reject cookies as required.  How to do this will depend on the browser you use.  We have provided further information below on how to check which browser you use and how to manage cookies.  Please bear in mind that if cookies are not enabled on your computer, your activities will be restricted to browsing this website and you will not be able to add products to your shopping bag and buy them.

**Checking which browser you use**

**If you are using a PC** \- go to 'Help' and select the 'About' option  
**If you are using a Mac** \- click on the Apple menu within the browser and select the 'About' option

Once you know which brower you are using, follow the instructions below to check if you have cookies enabled on your computer:  

**Checking cookies - PCs**

Microsoft Internet Explorer 6,7,8  
\- Go to 'Tools' at the top of your browser window. Select 'Internet options'. Click on the 'Privacy' tab  
\- Ensure that your Privacy level is set to Medium or below to enable cookies

Mozilla Firefox  
\- Go to 'Tools' and select Options  
\- Click the Privacy icon  
\- Click on Cookies and choose 'allow sites to set cookies'

Google Chrome  
\- Go to 'Tools' and select Options  
\- Click 'Under the Hood'  and select the 'Content settings' button within the 'Privacy' section  
\- Choose 'Allow local data to be set'  
  
---  
  
**Checking cookies – Macs**

Safari on OSX  
\- Click 'Safari' and select 'Preferences'   
\- Click 'Security' then 'Accept cookies'

Mozilla and Netscape on OSX  
\- Click on 'Mozilla' or 'Netscape' and select 'Preferences'  
\- Find ‘Cookies’ under 'Privacy & Security'  
\- Select 'Enable cookies for the originating web site only'

Microsoft Internet Explorer on OSX  
\- Click 'Explorer' and select 'Preferences'  
\- Find 'Cookies' under ‘Receiving Files’  
\- Select 'Never Ask' 

Opera  
\- Click 'Menu' and select 'Settings'  
\- Select 'Preferences' and then 'Advanced'   
\- Select 'Accept cookies'  

If you are not happy with the way that we use cookies then you should delete Evans cookies having visited the site, or you should browse the site using your browser’s anonymous usage setting (called “Incognito” in Chrome, “InPrivate” for Internet Explorer, "Private Browsing" in Firefox and Safari etc.)
